# Joshua Wilson

I'm a versatile coder with 7+ years of experience working with small teams and building killer applications with especially deep knowledge of building tools and services in Python, MongoDB, and AngularJS. I've worked in the scientific, financial, and now web services sectors. Always looking for a new challenge. @wilsojb is my handle.

Brooklyn, NY (919) 323-6369 wilsojb@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/wilsojb wilsojb.me

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineer, TripExpert, NYC

NOV 2015 - PRESENT

I'm developing a cross-platform mobile app (AngularJS, HTML/CSS, Cordova) and its backend service (Python, MongoDB) that complements www.tripexpert.com.

# Software Engineer, Hudson River Trading, NYC

APRIL 2011 - SEPT 2015

I spent most of my time developing internal tools and services in Python and MongoDB, as the company grew from 60-100+ employees. This is where I learned everything I know about systems programming, test-driven development lifecycles, and the data pipeline. I played an integral role in converting a legacy code base into a library of tools that helped their business internationally scale. My day consisted of reviewing pull requests, committing quick fixes and new features, and dealing with the occasional market outage.

# **Grad. Research Assistant,** University of North Carolina, NC

DEC 2008 - DEC 2010

Physics student finds a home in the Department of Physical Oceanography and studied numerical fluid dynamics there for a few years. All of my code from this period is published on github (http://wilsojb.io/pdelab). I had the opportunity to collect data on a ship in the Massachusetts Bay for two weeks at sea. It was a blast.

# Orientation Coordinator, Hendrix College, AR

JAN 2007 - SEPT 2007

Was responsible for executing the New Student and Parent Orientation 2007 programs which included corralling a staff of 70+ volunteers, planning a week of events, and sending students on trips around the state of Arkansas for the weekend (e.g. https://www.hendrix.edu/orientation/trips/).

My complete work history can be found on Linkedin.

#### CODE

Most proficient in Python, MongoDB, and AngularJS.

Working knowledge of Perl, Redis, Cordova, html/css, SQL, Unix/Bash, Node, and Scipy.org

**%E** atom, sublime, emacs, Sketch, and :q in vi

#### A LITTLE EXTRA

Backpacking is my favorite mode of transportation. I've done it through Europe and India so far. Currently planning an Inca trail hike. I love skiing and really anything outdoors. I'm a to-do list geek, a crontab nerd, and enjoy cooking big, elaborate meals for my friends and family. I'm always in the middle of 2-3 books and enjoy fixing the 1999 Jeep Cherokee that I share with my fiancé.

#### **EDUCATION / CERTIFICATIONS**

### General Assembly, NYC

Data Science Immersive, May 2016 (Currently enrolled)

I'm gaining experience writing web crawlers and using pandas, d3.js, and the core machine learning algorithms found in scikit-learn.

## MongoDB Certified Developer, NYC

Associate Level (#991405575), March 2016

# University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, NC

M.S. in Computational Physics, December 2010

Physics student finds a home in the Department of Physical Oceanography and studied numerical fluid dynamics there for a few years. All of my code from this period is published on github (http://wilsojb.io/pdelab). I had the opportunity to collect data on a ship in the Massachusetts Bay for two weeks at sea. It was a blast.

Publication: Numerical Approximations to the Boussinesq Equations (http://bit.ly/10GfzIn)

# Hendrix College, Conway, AR

B.A in Physics w/ minor in Computer Science, May 2008

I presented twice at the American Physical Society's annual conference. Here a the links to the abstracts: Laser Assisted Cancer Immunotherapy: Surface Irradiation (http://bit.ly/1kmwHWZ) and Construction and Calibration of a Six Degree of Freedom Thrust Sensor (http://bit.ly/1RlYpo4).